<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Leon's Blog(n)</title>
 <link href="http://localhost:4000/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://localhost:4000/"/>
 <updated></updated>
 <id>http://localhost:4000</id>
 <author>
   <name>Leon Yao</name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>It's the start of the third week of school</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/Start_third_week_of_school"/>
   <updated>2020-09-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/Start_third_week_of_school</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/blog//public/pages/Animations#中秋节.mp4&quot; style=&quot;display:inline&quot;&gt;Happy Mid Autumn Festival!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have some new ideas for projects, god knows if I ever finish any of them xD.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-Pdes heat/fluids game (ice age end of the world apocalypse where you assign heat sources in an apartment to keep people alive), planning to use ngsolve library.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-Text based job assignment fantasy game, planning to use gurobi to solve job assignment ip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-Apply finite element method to black scholes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m also looking at one of my supervisor’s papers. Yo, base golden ratio &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;\phi&lt;/script&gt; number systems are cool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In base &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;\phi&lt;/script&gt;, where &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;\phi&lt;/script&gt; is the larger root of &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;\phi^2 - \phi - 1 = 0&lt;/script&gt; i.e &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;\phi \approx 1.618&lt;/script&gt; numbers are written &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;\sum_{i=0}^{\infty}{a_n\phi^{-n}}&lt;/script&gt;, so it’s the normal decimal system except we have &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;\phi&lt;/script&gt; instead of $10$. 
It is also similar to binary, as &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;a_n&lt;/script&gt; are only allowed to be &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;0&lt;/script&gt; or &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;1&lt;/script&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike the base 10 system, there are many different ways to write the same number (Infinite ways according to Erdős).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, the number &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;1&lt;/script&gt; in base &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;10&lt;/script&gt; can be written as &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;1.0, 0.11, 0.1011&lt;/script&gt; in base &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;\phi&lt;/script&gt;, and there are trickier expansions such as $0.110110110110 … $ and $0.10101011010$. These can be shown with a little algebra.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details&gt; &lt;summary&gt; A little algebra showing the above &lt;/summary&gt;
$$
\begin{align}
\phi^2 - \phi - 1 &amp;amp;= 0 \text{ start with quadratic equation} \\
1 - \frac{1}{\phi} - \frac{1}{\phi^2} &amp;amp;= 0 \text{ divide both sides by } \phi \\
1 &amp;amp;= \frac{1}{\phi} + \frac{1}{\phi^2} \text{ rearrange, note that this would be } 0.11 \text{ in base } \phi  \\
  &amp;amp;= \frac{1}{\phi} + \frac{\frac{1}{\phi} + \frac{1}{\phi^2}}{\phi^2} \text{ sub in previous line for the 1 in the numerator of }\frac{1}{\phi^4} \\
  &amp;amp;= \frac{1}{\phi} + \frac{1}{\phi^3} + \frac{1}{\phi^4} \text{simplify, note that this would be } 0.1011 \text{ in base } \phi \\
  &amp;amp;= \frac{1}{\phi} + \frac{1}{\phi^3} + \frac{\frac{1}{\phi} + \frac{1}{\phi^2} }{\phi^4} \text{ repeat substitution process always on the greatest power term}
 \\
  &amp;amp;= \frac{1}{\phi} + \frac{1}{\phi^3} + \frac{1}{\phi^5} + \frac{1}{\phi^6} \\
  &amp;amp; \vdots 
\end{align} 
$$
which then becomes $$0.10101010...$$ in base $\phi$.
Other expansions such as $$0.110110110...$$ can be shown with a similar method, though you would replace the $1$ with $\frac{1}{\phi^2} - \frac{1}{\phi}$ in a different term (not always the greatest power one).  
&lt;/details&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>End of Second week of classes</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/Finishing_up_second_week"/>
   <updated>2020-09-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/Finishing_up_second_week</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This week is coming to a close. Worked on my Numerical algs assignment and made a little animation for the &lt;a class=&quot;sidebar-nav-item&quot; href=&quot;/blog//public/pages/Animations#Finite_Difference_Example.mp4&quot; style=&quot;display:inline&quot;&gt;first question&lt;/a&gt;
and the 2D version for the &lt;a class=&quot;sidebar-nav-item&quot; href=&quot;/blog//public/pages/Animations#Finite_Difference_Example_2D.mp4&quot; style=&quot;display:inline&quot;&gt;next question&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The former is the Finite Difference solution to &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;u''(x) = -(3 \cdot x + x^2) \cdot e^x&lt;/script&gt; on the domain &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;[0, 1]&lt;/script&gt; with &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;0&lt;/script&gt; boundary conditions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The latter is the Finite Difference solution to &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;\delta u = -2 \cdot (x + y - x^2 - y^2)&lt;/script&gt; on the domain &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;[0, 1]^2&lt;/script&gt; with &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;0&lt;/script&gt; boundary conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Second week of classes</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/Second_week_of_grad_school"/>
   <updated>2020-09-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/Second_week_of_grad_school</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It’s the second week of classes! Still mainly syllabus stuff.
Messed around with the starter code of the Computational PDEs course to make  &lt;a class=&quot;sidebar-nav-item&quot; href=&quot;/blog//public/pages/Animations#Heartbeat_final.mp4&quot; style=&quot;display:inline&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>School starts in 2 Weeks!</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/School_starts_in_two_weeks"/>
   <updated>2020-08-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/School_starts_in_two_weeks</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Read the Leviathan series! Excited for Leviathan falls this fall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also read Ao Ashi, cool soccer manga like Blue Lock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Been learning “Autumn Leaves in 10 styles” on the piano. Learned the first 3 styles so far, 7 left. The funky latin looks fun.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>School starts in 3 weeks!</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/School_starts_in_three_weeks"/>
   <updated>2020-08-08T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/School_starts_in_three_weeks</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve learned a new song called &lt;a class=&quot;sidebar-nav-item&quot; href=&quot;/blog//Piano#&quot; style=&quot;display:inline&quot;&gt; Tea for Two &lt;/a&gt; which was arranged by Pierre-Yves Plat and composed by Vincent Youmans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also been trying to get my old physics assignment up on the blog. It’s written in C++, so I’m trying to get Google NACL to work but its making be me pretty salty so far …&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>John 3-7. You should not be surprised at my saying, You must be born again.</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/Rebirth"/>
   <updated>2020-07-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/Rebirth</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Restarting blog. Let’s see how long I can keep this updated for. This summer I didn’t do that much, but there’s some &lt;a href=&quot;/blog//Animations&quot;&gt;animations&lt;/a&gt; I will show off! I also played a lot of &lt;a href=&quot;/blog//piano&quot;&gt;piano&lt;/a&gt; as well!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Week 13</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/Week12"/>
   <updated>2019-07-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/Week12</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This week I am still trying to categorize capped trivial tangles into families.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- 

Last week I tried to calculate the 'small arc' invariant for some capped trivial tangles, but i misunderstand what makes the invariant small. I thought small meant that the last part of the chain dissapears, but I only need to count the number of vertices. 

So far I know that the immersed curve invariant corresponds some set of curves on the $4$ punctured disk.  
It turns out that adding positive or negative twists to the ends of the tangle corresponds to switching the punctures on the $4$ punctured disk, which in turns simplifies the tangle. I am tasked with calculating the small arc for different rational tangles, and experimenting to see how different twists affect the invariant. (The invariant is unique up to these kinds of twists). 

I am also tasked with categorizing the capped trivial tangles into families. So far I know of 3 families. 

The first family comes from the quotient of the trefoil knot. 
&lt;img src = &quot;/blog//assets/img/7-15-2020-1.jpg&quot;&gt; 
For each $n &gt; 0$, we can twists the designated strands to get a different tangle, and each of these tangles correspond to the quotient tangle of a torus knot. So far it seems that the nth tangle corresponds to the nth torus knot, though I still need to verify some more examples for higher $n$. I wonder how I would prove this? I would need to show the twists on the torus correspond to the n twists on the designated strands. 

The second family from surgery on the first family. I am not sure how exactly it is done, but we can take the designated strand and &quot;wrap&quot; it around the the top band. The case $m = 1$ is shown on the right.
&lt;img src = &quot;/blog//assets/img/7-15-2020-2.jpg&quot;&gt; 

The third family comes surgery on the second family. For fixed $n, m$, we can let $k$ be some intger, and add $k$ twists inside the rectange (positive means positively sloped twists, negative is negatively sloped twists). 
&lt;img src = &quot;/blog//assets/img/7-15-2020-3.jpg&quot;&gt; 

I should be able to categorize all of the quotient tangles I have found so far with 5 crossings or less in these 3 families. From 5 crossings onward, I will hopefully find some more interesting families.   --&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Immersed Curve Invariant</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/ImmersedCurveInvariant"/>
   <updated>2019-07-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/ImmersedCurveInvariant</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I talked with Ben Garbuz today and he taught me a bit about the Immersed Curve Invariant and how it’s related to Khovanov homology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given a 4 ended tangle, we will designate each of the 4 ends to become part of a boundary of a 3 punctured disk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, given the rational tangle with 1 negative twist, we would transform the tangle into the following diagram&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/ImmersedCurveInvariant/ImmersedCurveInvariant-1.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We then stretch the strand of tangle that does not have a star end point, such that so the end points of the red curve on the punctures correspond to the endpoints of the tangle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will label the diagram will the following symbols, so that we can represent the homotopy class of the curve in a simpler way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/ImmersedCurveInvariant/ImmersedCurveInvariant-2.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From here, we can construct the chain complex over the ring generated by the $S, D$ cobordisms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been told that we assume the curve always has a counterclockwise orientation, but it doesn’t match up with the program…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We do this by splitting the curve up into whenever it touches one of the dark green lines. The above curve would have 3 sections.
For every section that doesn’t go into puncture, we will label it by S or D, depending on which of the S, D directions it follows on the boundary. From there, we construct the chain complex by with chain groups represented by the black or white dots, and boundary operators labelled with S and D.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above curve would have chain complex&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/ImmersedCurveInvariant/ImmersedCurveInvariant-3.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The curve can be used to calculate Khovanov Homology of the numerator closure of the tangle in the following way. For unreduced Khovanov homology, we draw the following orange curve. We then inspect the intersections between the red tangle curve and the orange curve. The number of intersections tells us how many copies of $\mathbb{F}$ there are in the homology. So here there would be 5 copies (This seems wrong, I think Ben told me you need to draw it in the minimal form, but I am not sure how to do that)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/ImmersedCurveInvariant/ImmersedCurveInvariant-4.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From there, there is a process upon where you first assign gradings to the intersections between the orange curve and the dark straight lines, and then from there you can follow the orange curve to find the gradings of the groups.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Week 11</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/Week11"/>
   <updated>2019-07-13T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/Week11</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last week I tried to calculate the ‘small arc’ invariant for some capped trivial tangles, but i misunderstand what makes the invariant small. I thought small meant that the last part of the chain dissapears, but I only need to count the number of vertices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far I know that the immersed curve invariant corresponds some set of curves on the $4$ punctured disk.&lt;br /&gt;
It turns out that adding positive or negative twists to the ends of the tangle corresponds to switching the punctures on the $4$ punctured disk, which in turns simplifies the tangle. I am tasked with calculating the small arc for different rational tangles, and experimenting to see how different twists affect the invariant. (The invariant is unique up to these kinds of twists).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am also tasked with categorizing the capped trivial tangles into families. So far I know of 3 families.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first family comes from the quotient of the trefoil knot. 
&lt;img src=&quot;/blog//assets/img/7-15-2020-1.jpg&quot; /&gt; 
For each $n &amp;gt; 0$, we can twists the designated strands to get a different tangle, and each of these tangles correspond to the quotient tangle of a torus knot. So far it seems that the nth tangle corresponds to the nth torus knot, though I still need to verify some more examples for higher $n$. I wonder how I would prove this? I would need to show the twists on the torus correspond to the n twists on the designated strands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second family from surgery on the first family. I am not sure how exactly it is done, but we can take the designated strand and “wrap” it around the the top band. The case $m = 1$ is shown on the right.
&lt;img src=&quot;/blog//assets/img/7-15-2020-2.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third family comes surgery on the second family. For fixed $n, m$, we can let $k$ be some intger, and add $k$ twists inside the rectange (positive means positively sloped twists, negative is negatively sloped twists). 
&lt;img src=&quot;/blog//assets/img/7-15-2020-3.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I should be able to categorize all of the quotient tangles I have found so far with 5 crossings or less in these 3 families. From 5 crossings onward, I will hopefully find some more interesting families.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Week 10</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/Week10"/>
   <updated>2019-07-06T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/Week10</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last week I used the KH program to calculate chain complexes for some simple tangles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week I am tasked with finding the minimal number of twists on the tangle such that the tail of the arc invariant chain complex dissapears.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Week 9</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/Week9"/>
   <updated>2019-06-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/Week9</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last week I continued to polish tangles. I find it tricky to perform “band” R1 moves, as there are often strands that go through the band, and it is hard to visualize what happens to the band.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week I am tasked with using the python program to calculate Khovanov refinement for simple tangles. It is interesting to convert the drawings I’ve made to the format the program uses.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Week 8</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/Week8"/>
   <updated>2019-06-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/Week8</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This week I polished the simplified tangles. I am planning to create a site using the knot atlas template, to display invariants for each tangle.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Week 7</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/Week7"/>
   <updated>2019-06-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/Week7</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This week I redrew some capped trivial tangles. I tried to draw them as simplified as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Week 6</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/Week6"/>
   <updated>2019-06-08T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/Week6</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I moved the Capped-Trivial-Tangles to a different site so I could add some buttons that show the construction of the tangle.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Week 5</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/Week5"/>
   <updated>2019-06-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/Week5</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This week I drew some more Capped Trivial Tangles.
I also learned about a bit about the refined khovanov homology. 
I am excited to learn more about spectral sequences!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Chain Complexes</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/ChainComplexes"/>
   <updated>2019-05-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/ChainComplexes</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;style&gt;
div.a {
  margin-left: 200px;
  width: 5px;
  height: 5px;
  top: -45px;
  transform: rotate(90deg);
  position: relative;
}
img {
    display: block;
    margin-left: auto;
    margin-right: auto;
    }
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;!-- If you look at the definition of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chain_complex#Definitions&quot;&gt;Chain Complex &lt;/a&gt; you will see a lot of scary words like &quot;differential&quot; and &quot;cochain&quot;. 

I want to try and motivate the usefulness of Chain Complexes without using any of those hard words.  --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s begin with some geometry. Take a piece of paper. Roll it up into a cylinder by gluing along an edge. Then fold the ends into a doughnut shape by gluing along a circle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a hard question to answer. Is there a way to deform the doughnut back into the flat piece of paper with using scissors?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you try it yourself you would probably guess not. One of the things you might say is a problem is that the donut has this hole in the middle.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Fundamental Group</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/FundamentalGroup"/>
   <updated>2019-05-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/FundamentalGroup</id>
   <content type="html">
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Week 4</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/Week4"/>
   <updated>2019-05-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/Week4</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;style&gt;
div.a {
  margin-left: 200px;
  width: 5px;
  height: 5px;
  top: -45px;
  transform: rotate(90deg);
  position: relative;
}
img {
    display: block;
    margin-left: auto;
    margin-right: auto;
    }
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week I reviewed the bracket polynomial on tangles. &lt;a href=&quot;/blog//2019/05/25/BracketOnTangles.html&quot;&gt; The formula for the bracket of a sum of tangles is pretty nice!&lt;/a&gt;
I wonder if there is a corresponding formula for multiplication of tangles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started drawing immersed curves as well. I am still a bit shaky on the construction, but it seems like a cool invariant for a tangle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;/blog//assets/CurveDrawing.pdf&quot; style=&quot;width:600px; height:500px;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Brackets Polynomial for Tangles</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/BracketOnTangles"/>
   <updated>2019-05-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/BracketOnTangles</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;style&gt;

img {
    display: block;
    margin-left: auto;
    margin-right: auto;
    }

a {
  color: #900;
  text-decoration: none;
}

a:hover {
  color: red;
  position: relative;
}

a[data]:hover:after {
  content: attr(data);
  padding: 4px 8px;
  color: rgba(0,0,0,0.5);
  position: absolute;
  left: 0;
  top: 100%;
  white-space: nowrap;
  z-index: 2;
  border-radius: 5px ;
  background: rgba(0,0,0,0.5);
}

b {
    display: none;
    height:30px;
    top: -50px;
    width:290px;
    text-align: center;
    position:relative;
}

a:hover + b {
    display: block;
}​



&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;!-- 
&lt;a href=&quot;http://127.0.0.1:4000/ResearchJournal//2019/05/13/RationalTangles.html#tangle&quot;&gt;Tangle&lt;/a&gt;  --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bracket polynomial of a &lt;a href=&quot;/blog//2019/05/13/RationalTangles.html#tangle&quot;&gt;Tangle&lt;/a&gt; $T$ counts the ways to smooth a tangle into the infinity tangle $)($ and the zero tangle &lt;font size=&quot;+2&quot;&gt; &lt;span&gt;
    &amp;#xFE35;.
    &lt;span style=&quot;position:relative; left:-37px; top:0.5px;&quot;&gt;&amp;#xFE36;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is easiest to calculate the bracket polynomial with a &lt;b&gt;resolution tree&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some examples of resolution trees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Example 1: $T_1$ - Tangle with 1 crossing 
&lt;img src=&quot;/blog//assets/img/1twist.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the left child, we have performed $0$ smoothing on the crossing in the middle of the knot, while on the right child, we have performed an $\infty$ smoothing on the crossing instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Example 2: $T_2$ - Tangle with 2 crossings&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog//assets/img/2twists.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each node in the resolution tree corresponds a state of the tangle where some of the crossings have been smoothed. The left child of each node represents a $0$ smoothing while the right child represents an $\infty$ smoothing. I ordered the crossings arbitrary from left to right, so the first level represents the choices for smoothing the crossing on the left.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each leaf node of the “resolution tree” corresponds to a combination of smoothings for each crossing. For each crossing, we can smoothing the crossing in one of two ways&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog//assets/img/SplittingRule.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A exercise that is left to the reader is that each leaf node will either look like infinity tangle $)($ or the zero tangle with $0$ or more circles in between number of circles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here the variable for the polynomial is $A$ instead of the usual variable x (perhaps because x looks too much like a crossing).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For tangle $T$, then we define the bracket polynomial $\langle T \rangle := P_0(A)\langle )( \rangle + P_{\infty}(A)\langle$ &lt;font size=&quot;+2&quot;&gt; &lt;span&gt;
    &amp;#xFE35;$\rangle$
    &lt;span style=&quot;position:relative; left:-42px; top:0.5px;&quot;&gt;&amp;#xFE36;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So for the tangle $T_1$ in Example 1, we have that &lt;br /&gt;
$\langle T_1 \rangle := A \langle )( \rangle + A^{-1}\langle$ &lt;font size=&quot;+2&quot;&gt; &lt;span&gt;
    &amp;#xFE35;$\rangle$
    &lt;span style=&quot;position:relative; left:-42px; top:0.5px;&quot;&gt;&amp;#xFE36;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that for a tangle with $n$ crossings, we have $2^n$ possible smoothings&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For any two tangles $G$ and $H$, we can “add” $G$ and $H$ together in the following way: 
&lt;img src=&quot;/blog//assets/img/TangleAddition.jpg&quot; /&gt;
-credit to &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/o6UnPngxbOo?t=192&quot;&gt;Matthew Salmone&lt;/a&gt; for the drawing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out the formula for the bracket of the sum of tangles is really nice!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let two knots $G, H$ have bracket polynomials given by the coefficients $(P_0, P_\infty), (Q_0, Q_{\infty})$. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Then the bracket polynomial of $G + H$ is given by&lt;br /&gt;
$(P_0 \cdot Q_0, P_\infty \cdot Q_0 + P_0 \cdot Q_\infty + \delta \cdot P_\infty \cdot Q_\infty)$.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is the algebraic mess saying? As an example, let $G$ be the 1 twist tangle and $H$ be the 2 twist tangle. Then $G+H$ looks like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog//assets/img/1twistPlus2twists.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s draw the resolution tree for $G+H$&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog//assets/img/3twists.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(I added circles at the bottom just to highlight the leaf nodes)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looks complicated right. Well let’s see what happens if zoom in on the 3 nodes in the bottom left hand corner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog//assets/img/3twistsZoomedIn.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;​If you squint your eyes, you can imagine that the 3 nodes are really just a copy of the 1twist resolution tree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One might then realize that you can draw the  resolution for $G + H$ in the following way:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Draw the resolution tree for $G$&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For each state in the tree, add the $H$ tangle&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The leaf nodes now have new crossings because of the $H$ tangle, so resolve those crossings to complete the tree&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this construction, the formula for the bracket becomes clearer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to smooth $G + H$ into the zero tangle, you have to smooth both $G$ and $H$ into the zero tangles. Recall that $P_0$ is the sum of the ways to smooth $G$ into the $0$ tangle, and $Q_0$ is the sum of the ways to smooth $H$ into the $0$ tangle, so each term in the product $P_0 \cdot Q_0$ will correspond to a combination of smoothings that smooth $G+H$ into the $0$ tangle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One useful application of tangles is that we can “close” them up to form knots, and the invariants of knots become easy to calculate using the invariants of the tangle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- &lt;img src=&quot;/blog//assets/img/3twistsZoomedIn.jpg&quot; title=&quot;A mathematician might say that the 2 trees are isomorphic, meaning that each node of the tree on left the gets mapped to a corresponding node of the tree on the right, such that the structure of the tree is preserved. See more into graph theory if you like trees!&quot;&gt; --&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Week 3</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/Week3"/>
   <updated>2019-05-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/Week3</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Summary of Week 3:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Mainly read more of Dror’s paper. Calculated some of Khovanov homology groups for simple knots.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Met up with some other NSERC participants over Zoom. Was awkward but fun! Hopefully there will be more people interested in presenting their research halfway through the summer.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I also drew some examples capped-trivial tangles. They are interesting to draw, though sometimes I find it difficult to see how to simplify them.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Rational Tangles</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/RationalTangles"/>
   <updated>2019-05-13T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/RationalTangles</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;style&gt;
    img {
    display: block;
    margin-left: auto;
    margin-right: auto;
    }
    details {
        margin-left: 5%;
    }
    summary {
        margin-left: -5%;
        position : relat;
    }
    .tangle{

    }
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to share a particular kind of tangle which I thought has a cool correspondence with rational numbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post will be regurgitating the video series given by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLL0ATV5XYF8BfT8CmmzKnfTlf3V9hQgj9&quot;&gt;Matthew Salomone&lt;/a&gt;. I highly recommend you check out this series if you have a background in topology or group theory, and you are interested in knot theory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;tangle&quot;&gt;
A tangle is a diagram of a small part of a knot. One way to construct tangles to draw a circle on the knot diagram such that the knot intersects the circle at exactly 4 places. Here is an example of a knot diagram. 
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/blog//assets/img/KnotDiagramExample.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is an example of a tangle.
&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/blog//assets/img/TangleExample.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
The purple arrows point to crossings inherent to the knot diagram, while the blue arrows represent the 4 intersections between the circle and the knot diagram. To save on ink we still stop drawing the circle from now on and only draw the intersections, but know that there is a circle that seperates the tangle from the rest of the knot at exactly 4 points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One particular type of tangle is called a rational tangle. We construct rational tangles in the following way:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog//assets/img/RationalTangles.jpg&quot; class=&quot;center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is an example of a rational tangle (again all of these were drawn by Matthew Solomone).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog//assets/img/RationalTangleExample.jpg&quot; class=&quot;center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of writing $T$ to represent doing a twist, we will generalize this operation slightly by using an addition symbol.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog//assets/img/TangleAdditionWithExamples.jpg&quot; class=&quot;center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note boxes with $G$ and $H$ in them represent any arbitrary tangles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, instead of writing $R$ to represent rotating, we will write 1/G. This allows us to define multiplication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog//assets/img/TangleMultiplicationWithExamples.jpg&quot; class=&quot;center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the last picture, notice we defined the “negative” of a knot. The reason this is well defined can be show with the following image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog//assets/img/TwistInverse.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First note that when we say two tangles are equal, we mean one can be stretched and squeezed into the other without moving the 4 interesection dots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means that taking any knot and performing $TRTRTR$ can be deformed back into the original knot. We can also write this as meaning&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script type=&quot;math/tex; mode=display&quot;&gt;T(R(T(R(T(R(G)))))) = [1] + \frac{[-1]}{[1] + \frac{[-1]}{[1] + \frac{[-1]}{G}}} = G&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notice that if take any number $x$, the algebraic statement also holds for normal numbers. Is this a coincidence?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script type=&quot;math/tex; mode=display&quot;&gt;1 + \frac{-1}{1 + \frac{-1}{1 + \frac{-1}{x}}}    = x&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;details&gt; &lt;summary&gt; Messy Algebra showing the above &lt;/summary&gt;
$$ \begin{equation*}
    \begin{split}
        1 + \frac{-1}{1 + \frac{-1}{  1 + \frac{-1}{x}}} &amp;amp;= 1 + \frac{-1}{\frac{-1}{1 + \frac{x - 1}{x}}} \\
        &amp;amp;= 1 + \frac{-1}{1 + \frac{-x}{x - 1}} \\
        &amp;amp;= 1 + \frac{-1}{\frac{x - 1 - x}{x - 1}}\\
        &amp;amp;= 1 + x - 1 = x \\
    \end{split}    
\end{equation*}
$$
&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
What this really means is that if we defined $G + [-1]$ to mean performing $RTRTR$ operation on $G$, then for any tangle $G$, $G + [1] + [-1] = G$. It is almost like these tangles behave like numbers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This also implies that $[1] + [-1] = [0]$ where $[0]$ is the empty tangle. I’ll leave it as an exercise to the reader to show this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Cool fact! $R$ and $T$ operations have inverses&lt;/summary&gt; 
We note that the $R$ operation has an inverse. You can see geometrically that $R^2 = I$, meaning that if you rotate by 90 degrees 2 times you end up with the same tangle (this is due to the vertical symmetry we started with at with empty tangle). Therefore the inverse of $R, R^{-1}$, is equal to itself. 

We also note that the $T$ operation has an inverse. The proof that
$TRTRTR = I$ can be seen with this animation below. Note that we say tangles are equal when we stretch and bend one tangle to another, without breaking or tearing any of the strands. 

&lt;img src=&quot;/blog//assets/img/TwistInverse.gif&quot; /&gt;

Thus, we let the inverse of $T, T^{-1} = RTRTR$
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The main is reason I feel this is a cool construction is because of the way we can represent these tangle diagrams as rational numbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we construct these tangles with $R$ and $T$ operations, it is clear that each sequence of letters of $R, T$ determines a tangle. For example, the sequence $TTTTTRTTRTTT$ produces the tangle in the previous example, as seen here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog//assets/img/Tangle.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, we first identify every sequence of $R, T, R^{-1}，T^{-1}$ with a sequence of integers. We will first cancel out the chunks of $R$s and $R^{-1}$s and $T$s, $T^{-1}$s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script type=&quot;math/tex; mode=display&quot;&gt;RRRR^{-1}TRTT^{-1}TTTRRR^{-1} = RRTRTTTR = R^2TRT^3R&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note we also shorten consecutive strings of the same letter using exponents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After shortening, we see that every sequence is of the form $R^{a_0}T^{a_1}R^{a_2}T^{a_3} … $ for some integers $a_i$.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will then adopt the convention that to get from a sequence of  integers to a tangle, we treat each integer as an exponent for the corresponding operation (starting with a twist).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example:
$3, -4, -10, 2 \iff  T^3R^{-4}T^{-10}R^2$&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why is this a useful encoding?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The $R$ and $T$ operations above are specific examples of the more general operations $+$ and $\cdot$.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recall that the R and T operations satisfiy TRTRTR = I.
It turns out there are operations rational numbers that this same equation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let $r(x) = -\frac{1}{x}, t(x) = x+1$.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We see that $r^2(x) = \frac{-1}{\frac{-1}{x}} = x$.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can show with a bit of algebra that $t(r(t(r(t(r(x)))))) = x$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt; Beware of Messy algebra &lt;/summary&gt;
$$
\begin{equation*}
    \begin{split}
        t(r(t(r(t(r(x)))))) &amp;amp;= t(r(t(r(t(-\frac{1}{x})))))) \\ 
                            &amp;amp;= t(r(t(r(-\frac{1}{x} + 1))))) \\
                            &amp;amp;= t(r(t(\frac{-1}{(-\frac{1}{x} + 1)}))) \\
                            &amp;amp;= t(r(\frac{-1}{(-\frac{1}{x} + 1)} + 1)) \\
                            &amp;amp;= t(\frac{-1}{\frac{-1}{-\frac{1}{x} + 1} + 1}) \\
                            &amp;amp;= \frac{-1}{\frac{-1}{-\frac{1}{x} + 1} + 1} + 1 \\
                            &amp;amp;= \frac{-1}{\frac{-1}{\frac{x - 1}{x}} + 1} + 1 \\
                            &amp;amp;= \frac{-1}{\frac{-x}{x - 1} + 1} + 1 \\
                            &amp;amp;= \frac{-1}{\frac{-x + (x - 1)}{x - 1}} + 1 \\
                            &amp;amp;= x - 1 + 1 = x \\
    \end{split}    
\end{equation*}
$$
&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Using these operations, we can turn the sequence of integers into a rational number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will take the sequence of integers and alternate between applying the $r$ and $t$ functions on the number built up so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For $3, -4, -10, 2$, this would look like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script type=&quot;math/tex; mode=display&quot;&gt;(((3 \cdot \frac{-1}{4}) + (-10)) \cdot \frac{1}{2}&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out these operations encapsulate the twist and rotation operations on tangle. If you take two tangles G and H, and convert them to their continued fraction representation, and then&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Isn’t this cool? This means that if you add or multiply rational tangles together&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Phew, if you made it this far, you are now an expert on rational tangles. Pat yourself on the back!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few questions you might consider:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are there tangles that are not rational tangles? By which I mean, tangles that cannot be constructed by starting from the empty tangle and performing the Twist and Rotation operations?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In general proving that such a tangle is difficult. 
&lt;!-- Given an arbitrary tangle, one to way prove it can be constructed from R and T operations is to give a sequence of such operations, and then twist and bend the tangle such that it matches up.  --&gt;
&lt;!-- It is usually easier to prove that it cannot be constructed.  --&gt;
One way to prove a given tangle is not rational is by finding things called “invariants”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An simple example of an invariant can be found in rock-paper-scissors. Let’s say we have two players Billbert and Billiam, who play a number of rounds of rock-papers-scissors. Let’s also say that a player gets +1 if they win and -1 if lose and 0 if they draw. Then after every round, we notice that the sum of the players scores is always 0 (these are called zero sum games, as the sum is invariant at 0). What this means is that, if ever the scores of two the players added up to something nonzero, then we know the scores of the two players could not come from watching Billbert and Billiam playing a fair game of rock paper scissors (perhaps Billiam is cheating).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going back to tangles, we need a property of tangle that does not change when we rotate or twist. If we can calculate such an invariant for empty tangle and for the given tangle, and the invariants are not equal, then it must be that the given tangle is not rational.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of my research this summer will be to calculate such an invariant, called the Khovanov Homology, for certain tangles. Wish me luck!&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Week 2</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/Week2"/>
   <updated>2019-05-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/Week2</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This week I had some freedom to try different things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I plan to host a mini conference for UBC NSERC and WLI participants online. 
So far half the participants have responded to my survey, and most of them are interested 
in a mini-conference. It’ll definitely be interesting to host on zoom. I need to be very careful as I know zoom has some unexpected bugs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was thinking that it would be interesting to see if there are any patterns between colourability and the different polynomials I’ve learned.
I think I would be able to write Knot Colouring as an Integer program, as it is similar enough to graph colouring. 
I obtained a Gurobi Academic license (Gurobi is an integer program solver), and I will try to see if my integer programs 
give me the correct results on different chromatic numbers for knots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve still be reading Dror Bar Natan’s paper on computing Khovanov Homology. It’s been slow, but I am making some progress. I wonder if I can think of 
the two vector spaces associated with each cycle in terms of electric charge. Then, when we merge or break cycles, do the maps correspond to cancelling or creating charge?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve also been reviewing topology. I read the section in the Knot book corresponding to Knot complements. 
They don’t say much about it, but I learned some new topological facts (which I was not expecting to). 
I never realized that homeomorphisms let you cut and glue manifolds, as long as the gluing is consistent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog//assets/img/TorusCutting.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it’s because you can go from the 3D representation to the 2D square with sides identified, and then shift the parts of the square 
so that when you go back to 3D, the torus becomes twisted. I need to read more about this.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Week 1</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/Week1"/>
   <updated>2019-05-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/Week1</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Summary of Week 1: 
It was definitely the calm before the storm this week. I mainly read up on Knot Theory and attended online lectures. I have started reading Dror Bar-Natan’s paper and it is interesting but difficult (Why is it called height if we draw the diagram sideways from left to right ahhhh).&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>First-Post!</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/test"/>
   <updated>2019-04-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/test</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Success! Tonight marks the start of my summer research blog. I will periodically update this blog with interesting knot theory bits I find throughout the summer.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
