<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-04-17T10:15:09-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Leon’s Blog(n)</title><subtitle>Just some math notes, piano recordings, and animations</subtitle><author><name>Leon Yao</name></author><entry><title type="html">Going home in a week!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/Going-home-tomorrow" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Going home in a week!" /><published>2021-04-16T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-04-16T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/Going%20home%20tomorrow</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/Going-home-tomorrow">&lt;p&gt;I should add a script to unmute on fullscreen in the animations section! Also need a script to kill local runs of this blog. Also should sort videos by date in sports section&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trying to learn the rainbow flick, but it’s hard to keep it in the air after it goes over my head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;video width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; controls=&quot;&quot; loop=&quot;&quot; autoplay=&quot;&quot; muted=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;source src=&quot;/blog//assets/Sports/rainbow_flick.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also learned some swing dancing yesterday! I am very not used to dancing 6/8 moves in 4/4 time. 
&lt;img src=&quot;/blog//assets/Sports/swing_dance.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:100%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Leon Yao</name></author><summary type="html">I should add a script to unmute on fullscreen in the animations section! Also need a script to kill local runs of this blog. Also should sort videos by date in sports section Trying to learn the rainbow flick, but it’s hard to keep it in the air after it goes over my head. Also learned some swing dancing yesterday! I am very not used to dancing 6/8 moves in 4/4 time.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Going home in a week!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/Going-home-in-a-week" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Going home in a week!" /><published>2021-04-10T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-04-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/Going%20home%20in%20a%20week</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/Going-home-in-a-week">&lt;p&gt;Competed at the Ontario University Atheltic’s Fencing competition last weekend!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did okish. First time competing in Sabre! Was pretty interesting to learn on the fly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; controls=&quot;&quot; loop=&quot;&quot; autoplay=&quot;&quot; muted=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;source src=&quot;/blog//assets/Sports/sabre_fencing_OUA.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog//assets/Sports/uwaterloo_team_ouas.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:100%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Had my PDES final today (was very hard). Have a couple projects and another final left!
&lt;img src=&quot;/blog//assets/Animations/加油.gif&quot; style=&quot;width:100%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Leon Yao</name></author><summary type="html">Competed at the Ontario University Atheltic’s Fencing competition last weekend! Did okish. First time competing in Sabre! Was pretty interesting to learn on the fly. Had my PDES final today (was very hard). Have a couple projects and another final left!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Terms almost over</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/AlmostDoneTerm-copy" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Terms almost over" /><published>2021-03-03T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-03-03T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/AlmostDoneTerm%20copy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/AlmostDoneTerm-copy">&lt;p&gt;Animated a bit today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; controls=&quot;&quot; loop=&quot;&quot; autoplay=&quot;&quot; muted=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;source src=&quot;/blog//assets/Animations/practice_43.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also trying to get jupyter notebook to work on heroku.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Leon Yao</name></author><summary type="html">Animated a bit today. Also trying to get jupyter notebook to work on heroku.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Reading weeks almost over</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/ReadingWeeksAlmostOver-copy" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reading weeks almost over" /><published>2021-02-24T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-02-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/ReadingWeeksAlmostOver%20copy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/ReadingWeeksAlmostOver-copy">&lt;p&gt;Learned how a pair of human eyes can calculate depth of objects.
&lt;img src=&quot;/blog//assets/Images/pair_eyes_views_depth.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/blog//assets/Images/disparity_maps.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Excited to go Toronto this weekend. Also excited for the fencing competition happening in a month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lost wallet recently, I appreciate the convenience of credits card a lot more now.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Leon Yao</name></author><summary type="html">Learned how a pair of human eyes can calculate depth of objects. Excited to go Toronto this weekend. Also excited for the fencing competition happening in a month. Lost wallet recently, I appreciate the convenience of credits card a lot more now.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">First Month of the new semester!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/FirstMonthOfNewTerm-copy" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="First Month of the new semester!" /><published>2021-01-25T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-01-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/FirstMonthOfNewTerm%20copy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/FirstMonthOfNewTerm-copy">&lt;p&gt;Some cool applications of partial derivatives.
&lt;img src=&quot;/blog//assets/Images/partial_derivatives.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trying to learn another dance!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;video width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; controls=&quot;&quot; loop=&quot;&quot; autoplay=&quot;&quot; muted=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;source src=&quot;/blog//assets/Sports/monster_practice_1.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also found out the math talk I gave 2 months ago was filmed!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/iDMZyFQLz6g?start=1826&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><author><name>Leon Yao</name></author><summary type="html">Some cool applications of partial derivatives. Trying to learn another dance! Also found out the math talk I gave 2 months ago was filmed!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Math Contest!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/MathContest" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Math Contest!" /><published>2020-12-07T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-12-07T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/MathContest</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/MathContest">&lt;p&gt;I competed in a math contest today called “Over 9000” with a friend. The contest consisted of a bunch of questions of the form “is N over 9000”, where $n$ was given by some complicated expression. We didn’t do too well xD.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought some of the rules and questions were interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog///assets/Images/Over9000rules.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My friend and I were initially aiming to get every question wrong, as the hosts had the rule that since every question boiled down to true or false, they would take the top 4 teams with highest absolute value score. Unofrtunately we consistently alternate between getting questions correct and getting questions wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog///assets/Images/Over9000question.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last question was game theory related, as the value of N would be 9001 if there were an odd number of people who voted it was such, and 1 otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, we were not allowed to collude between teams. There were an odd number of teams for this competition, so we would have all gotten the question right if we all voted that N was over 9000. Sadly it would later turn out of that some of voted under 9000, as N turned out to be 1, meaning that there were an even number of people who voted under 9000. Perhaps because they wanted to score higher than the other teams.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Leon Yao</name></author><summary type="html">I competed in a math contest today called “Over 9000” with a friend. The contest consisted of a bunch of questions of the form “is N over 9000”, where $n$ was given by some complicated expression. We didn’t do too well xD. I thought some of the rules and questions were interesting. My friend and I were initially aiming to get every question wrong, as the hosts had the rule that since every question boiled down to true or false, they would take the top 4 teams with highest absolute value score. Unofrtunately we consistently alternate between getting questions correct and getting questions wrong. The last question was game theory related, as the value of N would be 9001 if there were an odd number of people who voted it was such, and 1 otherwise. Unfortunately, we were not allowed to collude between teams. There were an odd number of teams for this competition, so we would have all gotten the question right if we all voted that N was over 9000. Sadly it would later turn out of that some of voted under 9000, as N turned out to be 1, meaning that there were an even number of people who voted under 9000. Perhaps because they wanted to score higher than the other teams.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Made Tofu!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/MadeTofu" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Made Tofu!" /><published>2020-11-11T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-11-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/MadeTofu</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/MadeTofu">&lt;p&gt;Made Tofu!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog///assets/Cooking/Tofu.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also learned how to sauder my body cords clip back on the chord. Was fun, it’s similar to making crafts with a hot glue gun, except with melted tin and lead instead of glue&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Leon Yao</name></author><summary type="html">Made Tofu! Also learned how to sauder my body cords clip back on the chord. Was fun, it’s similar to making crafts with a hot glue gun, except with melted tin and lead instead of glue</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Saw Buskers!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/SawBuskers" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Saw Buskers!" /><published>2020-11-06T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-11-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/SawBuskers</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/SawBuskers">&lt;p&gt;Wanted to go see a jazz show tonight but unfortunately the tickets were sold out. Luckily, there were some buskers on the street. The band was called “Just Fine”, and they were a really R&amp;amp;B band.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;video width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; controls=&quot;&quot; loop=&quot;&quot; autoplay=&quot;&quot; muted=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;source src=&quot;/blog///assets/Videos/JustFine.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;</content><author><name>Leon Yao</name></author><summary type="html">Wanted to go see a jazz show tonight but unfortunately the tickets were sold out. Luckily, there were some buskers on the street. The band was called “Just Fine”, and they were a really R&amp;amp;B band.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Halloween and Harrowing Heat equation</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/Halloween" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Halloween and Harrowing Heat equation" /><published>2020-10-31T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-10-31T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/Halloween</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/Halloween">&lt;p&gt;Made an animation for the finite element method with time dependence!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;video width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; controls=&quot;&quot; loop=&quot;&quot; autoplay=&quot;&quot; muted=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;source src=&quot;/blog///assets/Animations/Finite_Elements_Heat_Sim_Example.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also looks cool when you plot it out with time as the third dimension (Thanks Leonidas for the suggestion).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog///assets/Images/Finite_Elements_Heat_Sim_Contour.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then varied the initial condition. &lt;br /&gt;It starts at $u(x, 0) = \sin(0x)$ and ends up at $\sin(5\pi x)$ over the duration of the video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;video width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; controls=&quot;&quot; loop=&quot;&quot; autoplay=&quot;&quot; muted=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;source src=&quot;/blog///assets/Animations/contour_animation.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Auto covid form completer seems to work with schtasks, though it seems my computer needs to be on for it to run. Hopefully, I can run it in the background with some permissions, so I can leave my computer asleep&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Helped my friend with a halloween murder mystery party script.
I helped with some of the ideas. Was fun and tiring, as the players went in directions we did not anticipate. Also saw a lot of plotholes, its interesting to see the parts that needed more speficiation, generally crucial clues needed more details as player would make things up that weren’t exactly true, and such errors would cascade and cover up the real killers.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Leon Yao</name></author><summary type="html">Made an animation for the finite element method with time dependence! It also looks cool when you plot it out with time as the third dimension (Thanks Leonidas for the suggestion). I then varied the initial condition. It starts at $u(x, 0) = \sin(0x)$ and ends up at $\sin(5\pi x)$ over the duration of the video. Auto covid form completer seems to work with schtasks, though it seems my computer needs to be on for it to run. Hopefully, I can run it in the background with some permissions, so I can leave my computer asleep Helped my friend with a halloween murder mystery party script. I helped with some of the ideas. Was fun and tiring, as the players went in directions we did not anticipate. Also saw a lot of plotholes, its interesting to see the parts that needed more speficiation, generally crucial clues needed more details as player would make things up that weren’t exactly true, and such errors would cascade and cover up the real killers.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Reading Week, Part 2!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/Reading-week-is-halfway-done" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reading Week, Part 2!" /><published>2020-10-14T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-10-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/Reading-week-is-halfway-done</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/Reading-week-is-halfway-done">&lt;p&gt;Halfway through reading week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I worked on a possible research project, specifically the &lt;a href=&quot;/blog//public/pages/Research#chebyshev_optimization&quot;&gt;Integer Chebyshev Problem&lt;/a&gt;, which I think is a cool optimzation problem. It’ll be interesting to see if they are any real world applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m trying to get the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leoncyao/autofill_covid_self_assesment&quot;&gt;js script&lt;/a&gt; I wrote last week to automatically run once every day, but I don’t like using Windows Automatic Scheduler. Hopefully I can find a better script automater.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Leon Yao</name></author><summary type="html">Halfway through reading week. Today I worked on a possible research project, specifically the Integer Chebyshev Problem, which I think is a cool optimzation problem. It’ll be interesting to see if they are any real world applications. I’m trying to get the js script I wrote last week to automatically run once every day, but I don’t like using Windows Automatic Scheduler. Hopefully I can find a better script automater.</summary></entry></feed>