<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-09-22T04:06:26-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Leon’s Blog</title><subtitle>Just some math notes, piano recordings, and animations</subtitle><author><name>Leon Yao</name></author><entry><title type="html">Start_of_third_week_of_school</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/Start_third_week_of_school" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Start_of_third_week_of_school" /><published>2020-09-21T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-09-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/Start_third_week_of_school</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/Start_third_week_of_school">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/blog//public/pages/Animations#中秋节.mp4&quot; style=&quot;display:inline&quot;&gt;Happy Mid Autumn Festival!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have some new ideas for projects, god knows if I ever finish any of them xD.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-Pdes heat/fluids game (ice age end of the world apocalypse where you assign heat sources in an apartment to keep people alive), planning to use ngsolve library.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-Text based job assignment fantasy game, planning to use gurobi to solve job assignment ip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m also looking at one of my supervisor’s papers. Yo, base golden ratio &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;\phi&lt;/script&gt; number systems are cool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In base &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;\phi&lt;/script&gt;, where &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;\phi&lt;/script&gt; is the larger root of &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;\phi^2 - \phi - 1 = 0&lt;/script&gt; i.e &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;\phi \approx 1.618&lt;/script&gt; numbers are written &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;\sum_{i=0}^{\infty}{a_n\phi^{-n}}&lt;/script&gt;, so it’s the normal decimal system except we have &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;\phi&lt;/script&gt; instead of $10$. 
It is also similar to binary, as &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;a_n&lt;/script&gt; are only allowed to be &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;0&lt;/script&gt; or &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;1&lt;/script&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike the base 10 system, there are many different ways to write the same number (Infinite ways according to Erdős).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, the number &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;1&lt;/script&gt; in base &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;10&lt;/script&gt; can be written as &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;1.0, 0.11, 0.1011&lt;/script&gt; in base &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;\phi&lt;/script&gt;, and there are trickier expansions such as $0.110110110110 … $ and $0.10101011010$. These can be shown with a little algebra.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details&gt; &lt;summary&gt; A little algebra showing the above &lt;/summary&gt;
$$
\begin{align}
\phi^2 - \phi - 1 &amp;amp;= 0 \text{ start with quadratic equation} \\
1 - \frac{1}{\phi} - \frac{1}{\phi^2} &amp;amp;= 0 \text{ divide both sides by } \phi \\
1 &amp;amp;= \frac{1}{\phi} + \frac{1}{\phi^2} \text{ rearrange, note that this would be } 0.11 \text{ in base } \phi  \\
  &amp;amp;= \frac{1}{\phi} + \frac{\frac{1}{\phi} + \frac{1}{\phi^2}}{\phi^2} \text{ sub in previous line for the 1 in the numerator of }\frac{1}{\phi^4} \\
  &amp;amp;= \frac{1}{\phi} + \frac{1}{\phi^3} + \frac{1}{\phi^4} \text{simplify, note that this would be } 0.1011 \text{ in base } \phi \\
  &amp;amp;= \frac{1}{\phi} + \frac{1}{\phi^3} + \frac{\frac{1}{\phi} + \frac{1}{\phi^2} }{\phi^4} \text{ repeat substitution process always on the greatest power term}
 \\
  &amp;amp;= \frac{1}{\phi} + \frac{1}{\phi^3} + \frac{1}{\phi^5} + \frac{1}{\phi^6} \\
  &amp;amp; \vdots 
\end{align} 
$$
which then becomes $$0.10101010...$$ in base $\phi$.
Other expansions such as $$0.110110110...$$ can be shown with a similar method, though you would replace the $1$ with $\frac{1}{\phi^2} - \frac{1}{\phi}$ in a different term (not always the greatest power one).  
&lt;/details&gt;</content><author><name>Leon Yao</name></author><summary type="html">Happy Mid Autumn Festival! I have some new ideas for projects, god knows if I ever finish any of them xD. -Pdes heat/fluids game (ice age end of the world apocalypse where you assign heat sources in an apartment to keep people alive), planning to use ngsolve library. -Text based job assignment fantasy game, planning to use gurobi to solve job assignment ip. I’m also looking at one of my supervisor’s papers. Yo, base golden ratio number systems are cool. In base , where is the larger root of i.e numbers are written , so it’s the normal decimal system except we have instead of $10$. It is also similar to binary, as are only allowed to be or . Unlike the base 10 system, there are many different ways to write the same number (Infinite ways according to Erdős). For example, the number in base can be written as in base , and there are trickier expansions such as $0.110110110110 … $ and $0.10101011010$. These can be shown with a little algebra. A little algebra showing the above $$ \begin{align} \phi^2 - \phi - 1 &amp;amp;= 0 \text{ start with quadratic equation} \\ 1 - \frac{1}{\phi} - \frac{1}{\phi^2} &amp;amp;= 0 \text{ divide both sides by } \phi \\ 1 &amp;amp;= \frac{1}{\phi} + \frac{1}{\phi^2} \text{ rearrange, note that this would be } 0.11 \text{ in base } \phi \\ &amp;amp;= \frac{1}{\phi} + \frac{\frac{1}{\phi} + \frac{1}{\phi^2}}{\phi^2} \text{ sub in previous line for the 1 in the numerator of }\frac{1}{\phi^4} \\ &amp;amp;= \frac{1}{\phi} + \frac{1}{\phi^3} + \frac{1}{\phi^4} \text{simplify, note that this would be } 0.1011 \text{ in base } \phi \\ &amp;amp;= \frac{1}{\phi} + \frac{1}{\phi^3} + \frac{\frac{1}{\phi} + \frac{1}{\phi^2} }{\phi^4} \text{ repeat substitution process always on the greatest power term} \\ &amp;amp;= \frac{1}{\phi} + \frac{1}{\phi^3} + \frac{1}{\phi^5} + \frac{1}{\phi^6} \\ &amp;amp; \vdots \end{align} $$ which then becomes $$0.10101010...$$ in base $\phi$. Other expansions such as $$0.110110110...$$ can be shown with a similar method, though you would replace the $1$ with $\frac{1}{\phi^2} - \frac{1}{\phi}$ in a different term (not always the greatest power one).</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">End of Second week of classes</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/Finishing_up_second_week" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="End of Second week of classes" /><published>2020-09-17T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-09-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/Finishing_up_second_week</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/Finishing_up_second_week">&lt;p&gt;This week is coming to a close. Worked on my Numerical algs assignment and made a little animation for the &lt;a class=&quot;sidebar-nav-item&quot; href=&quot;/blog//public/pages/Animations#Finite_Difference_Example.mp4&quot; style=&quot;display:inline&quot;&gt;first question&lt;/a&gt;
and the 2D version for the &lt;a class=&quot;sidebar-nav-item&quot; href=&quot;/blog//public/pages/Animations#Finite_Difference_Example_2D.mp4&quot; style=&quot;display:inline&quot;&gt;next question&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The former is the Finite Difference solution to &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;u''(x) = -(3 \cdot x + x^2) \cdot e^x&lt;/script&gt; on the domain &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;[0, 1]&lt;/script&gt; with &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;0&lt;/script&gt; boundary conditions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The latter is the Finite Difference solution to &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;\delta u = -2 \cdot (x + y - x^2 - y^2)&lt;/script&gt; on the domain &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;[0, 1]^2&lt;/script&gt; with &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;0&lt;/script&gt; boundary conditions.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Leon Yao</name></author><summary type="html">This week is coming to a close. Worked on my Numerical algs assignment and made a little animation for the first question and the 2D version for the next question. The former is the Finite Difference solution to on the domain with boundary conditions. The latter is the Finite Difference solution to on the domain with boundary conditions.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Second week of classes</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/Second_week_of_grad_school" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Second week of classes" /><published>2020-09-14T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-09-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/Second_week_of_grad_school</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/Second_week_of_grad_school">&lt;p&gt;It’s the second week of classes! Still mainly syllabus stuff.
Messed around with the starter code of the Computational PDEs course to make  &lt;a class=&quot;sidebar-nav-item&quot; href=&quot;/blog//public/pages/Animations#Heartbeat_final.mp4&quot; style=&quot;display:inline&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Leon Yao</name></author><summary type="html">It’s the second week of classes! Still mainly syllabus stuff. Messed around with the starter code of the Computational PDEs course to make this.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">School starts in 2 Weeks!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/School_starts_in_two_weeks" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="School starts in 2 Weeks!" /><published>2020-08-23T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-08-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/School_starts_in_two_weeks</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/School_starts_in_two_weeks">&lt;p&gt;Read the Leviathan series! Excited for Leviathan falls this fall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also read Ao Ashi, cool soccer manga like Blue Lock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Been learning “Autumn Leaves in 10 styles” on the piano. Learned the first 3 styles so far, 7 left. The funky latin looks fun.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Leon Yao</name></author><summary type="html">Read the Leviathan series! Excited for Leviathan falls this fall. I also read Ao Ashi, cool soccer manga like Blue Lock. Been learning “Autumn Leaves in 10 styles” on the piano. Learned the first 3 styles so far, 7 left. The funky latin looks fun.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">School starts in 3 weeks!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/School_starts_in_three_weeks" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="School starts in 3 weeks!" /><published>2020-08-08T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-08-08T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/School_starts_in_three_weeks</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/School_starts_in_three_weeks">&lt;p&gt;I’ve learned a new song called &lt;a class=&quot;sidebar-nav-item&quot; href=&quot;/blog//Piano#&quot; style=&quot;display:inline&quot;&gt; Tea for Two &lt;/a&gt; which was arranged by Pierre-Yves Plat and composed by Vincent Youmans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also been trying to get my old physics assignment up on the blog. It’s written in C++, so I’m trying to get Google NACL to work but its making be me pretty salty so far …&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Leon Yao</name></author><summary type="html">I’ve learned a new song called Tea for Two which was arranged by Pierre-Yves Plat and composed by Vincent Youmans. Also been trying to get my old physics assignment up on the blog. It’s written in C++, so I’m trying to get Google NACL to work but its making be me pretty salty so far …</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">John 3-7. You should not be surprised at my saying, You must be born again.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/Rebirth" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="John 3-7. You should not be surprised at my saying, You must be born again." /><published>2020-07-28T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-07-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/Rebirth</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/Rebirth">&lt;p&gt;Restarting blog. Let’s see how long I can keep this updated for. This summer I didn’t do that much, but there’s some &lt;a href=&quot;/blog//Animations&quot;&gt;animations&lt;/a&gt; I will show off! I also played a lot of &lt;a href=&quot;/blog//piano&quot;&gt;piano&lt;/a&gt; as well!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Leon Yao</name></author><summary type="html">Restarting blog. Let’s see how long I can keep this updated for. This summer I didn’t do that much, but there’s some animations I will show off! I also played a lot of piano as well!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Week 13</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/Week12" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Week 13" /><published>2019-07-21T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-07-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/Week12</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/Week12">&lt;p&gt;This week I am still trying to categorize capped trivial tangles into families.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- 

Last week I tried to calculate the 'small arc' invariant for some capped trivial tangles, but i misunderstand what makes the invariant small. I thought small meant that the last part of the chain dissapears, but I only need to count the number of vertices. 

So far I know that the immersed curve invariant corresponds some set of curves on the $4$ punctured disk.  
It turns out that adding positive or negative twists to the ends of the tangle corresponds to switching the punctures on the $4$ punctured disk, which in turns simplifies the tangle. I am tasked with calculating the small arc for different rational tangles, and experimenting to see how different twists affect the invariant. (The invariant is unique up to these kinds of twists). 

I am also tasked with categorizing the capped trivial tangles into families. So far I know of 3 families. 

The first family comes from the quotient of the trefoil knot. 
&lt;img src = &quot;/blog//assets/img/7-15-2020-1.jpg&quot;&gt; 
For each $n &gt; 0$, we can twists the designated strands to get a different tangle, and each of these tangles correspond to the quotient tangle of a torus knot. So far it seems that the nth tangle corresponds to the nth torus knot, though I still need to verify some more examples for higher $n$. I wonder how I would prove this? I would need to show the twists on the torus correspond to the n twists on the designated strands. 

The second family from surgery on the first family. I am not sure how exactly it is done, but we can take the designated strand and &quot;wrap&quot; it around the the top band. The case $m = 1$ is shown on the right.
&lt;img src = &quot;/blog//assets/img/7-15-2020-2.jpg&quot;&gt; 

The third family comes surgery on the second family. For fixed $n, m$, we can let $k$ be some intger, and add $k$ twists inside the rectange (positive means positively sloped twists, negative is negatively sloped twists). 
&lt;img src = &quot;/blog//assets/img/7-15-2020-3.jpg&quot;&gt; 

I should be able to categorize all of the quotient tangles I have found so far with 5 crossings or less in these 3 families. From 5 crossings onward, I will hopefully find some more interesting families.   --&gt;</content><author><name>Leon Yao</name></author><summary type="html">This week I am still trying to categorize capped trivial tangles into families.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Immersed Curve Invariant</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/ImmersedCurveInvariant" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Immersed Curve Invariant" /><published>2019-07-17T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-07-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/ImmersedCurveInvariant</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/ImmersedCurveInvariant">&lt;p&gt;I talked with Ben Garbuz today and he taught me a bit about the Immersed Curve Invariant and how it’s related to Khovanov homology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given a 4 ended tangle, we will designate each of the 4 ends to become part of a boundary of a 3 punctured disk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, given the rational tangle with 1 negative twist, we would transform the tangle into the following diagram&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/ImmersedCurveInvariant/ImmersedCurveInvariant-1.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We then stretch the strand of tangle that does not have a star end point, such that so the end points of the red curve on the punctures correspond to the endpoints of the tangle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will label the diagram will the following symbols, so that we can represent the homotopy class of the curve in a simpler way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/ImmersedCurveInvariant/ImmersedCurveInvariant-2.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From here, we can construct the chain complex over the ring generated by the $S, D$ cobordisms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been told that we assume the curve always has a counterclockwise orientation, but it doesn’t match up with the program…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We do this by splitting the curve up into whenever it touches one of the dark green lines. The above curve would have 3 sections.
For every section that doesn’t go into puncture, we will label it by S or D, depending on which of the S, D directions it follows on the boundary. From there, we construct the chain complex by with chain groups represented by the black or white dots, and boundary operators labelled with S and D.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above curve would have chain complex&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/ImmersedCurveInvariant/ImmersedCurveInvariant-3.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The curve can be used to calculate Khovanov Homology of the numerator closure of the tangle in the following way. For unreduced Khovanov homology, we draw the following orange curve. We then inspect the intersections between the red tangle curve and the orange curve. The number of intersections tells us how many copies of $\mathbb{F}$ there are in the homology. So here there would be 5 copies (This seems wrong, I think Ben told me you need to draw it in the minimal form, but I am not sure how to do that)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/ImmersedCurveInvariant/ImmersedCurveInvariant-4.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From there, there is a process upon where you first assign gradings to the intersections between the orange curve and the dark straight lines, and then from there you can follow the orange curve to find the gradings of the groups.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Leon Yao</name></author><summary type="html">I talked with Ben Garbuz today and he taught me a bit about the Immersed Curve Invariant and how it’s related to Khovanov homology. Given a 4 ended tangle, we will designate each of the 4 ends to become part of a boundary of a 3 punctured disk. For example, given the rational tangle with 1 negative twist, we would transform the tangle into the following diagram We then stretch the strand of tangle that does not have a star end point, such that so the end points of the red curve on the punctures correspond to the endpoints of the tangle. We will label the diagram will the following symbols, so that we can represent the homotopy class of the curve in a simpler way. From here, we can construct the chain complex over the ring generated by the $S, D$ cobordisms. I have been told that we assume the curve always has a counterclockwise orientation, but it doesn’t match up with the program… We do this by splitting the curve up into whenever it touches one of the dark green lines. The above curve would have 3 sections. For every section that doesn’t go into puncture, we will label it by S or D, depending on which of the S, D directions it follows on the boundary. From there, we construct the chain complex by with chain groups represented by the black or white dots, and boundary operators labelled with S and D. The above curve would have chain complex The curve can be used to calculate Khovanov Homology of the numerator closure of the tangle in the following way. For unreduced Khovanov homology, we draw the following orange curve. We then inspect the intersections between the red tangle curve and the orange curve. The number of intersections tells us how many copies of $\mathbb{F}$ there are in the homology. So here there would be 5 copies (This seems wrong, I think Ben told me you need to draw it in the minimal form, but I am not sure how to do that) From there, there is a process upon where you first assign gradings to the intersections between the orange curve and the dark straight lines, and then from there you can follow the orange curve to find the gradings of the groups.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Week 11</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/Week11" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Week 11" /><published>2019-07-13T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-07-13T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/Week11</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/Week11">&lt;p&gt;Last week I tried to calculate the ‘small arc’ invariant for some capped trivial tangles, but i misunderstand what makes the invariant small. I thought small meant that the last part of the chain dissapears, but I only need to count the number of vertices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far I know that the immersed curve invariant corresponds some set of curves on the $4$ punctured disk.&lt;br /&gt;
It turns out that adding positive or negative twists to the ends of the tangle corresponds to switching the punctures on the $4$ punctured disk, which in turns simplifies the tangle. I am tasked with calculating the small arc for different rational tangles, and experimenting to see how different twists affect the invariant. (The invariant is unique up to these kinds of twists).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am also tasked with categorizing the capped trivial tangles into families. So far I know of 3 families.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first family comes from the quotient of the trefoil knot. 
&lt;img src=&quot;/blog//assets/img/7-15-2020-1.jpg&quot; /&gt; 
For each $n &amp;gt; 0$, we can twists the designated strands to get a different tangle, and each of these tangles correspond to the quotient tangle of a torus knot. So far it seems that the nth tangle corresponds to the nth torus knot, though I still need to verify some more examples for higher $n$. I wonder how I would prove this? I would need to show the twists on the torus correspond to the n twists on the designated strands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second family from surgery on the first family. I am not sure how exactly it is done, but we can take the designated strand and “wrap” it around the the top band. The case $m = 1$ is shown on the right.
&lt;img src=&quot;/blog//assets/img/7-15-2020-2.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third family comes surgery on the second family. For fixed $n, m$, we can let $k$ be some intger, and add $k$ twists inside the rectange (positive means positively sloped twists, negative is negatively sloped twists). 
&lt;img src=&quot;/blog//assets/img/7-15-2020-3.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I should be able to categorize all of the quotient tangles I have found so far with 5 crossings or less in these 3 families. From 5 crossings onward, I will hopefully find some more interesting families.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Leon Yao</name></author><summary type="html">Last week I tried to calculate the ‘small arc’ invariant for some capped trivial tangles, but i misunderstand what makes the invariant small. I thought small meant that the last part of the chain dissapears, but I only need to count the number of vertices. So far I know that the immersed curve invariant corresponds some set of curves on the $4$ punctured disk. It turns out that adding positive or negative twists to the ends of the tangle corresponds to switching the punctures on the $4$ punctured disk, which in turns simplifies the tangle. I am tasked with calculating the small arc for different rational tangles, and experimenting to see how different twists affect the invariant. (The invariant is unique up to these kinds of twists). I am also tasked with categorizing the capped trivial tangles into families. So far I know of 3 families. The first family comes from the quotient of the trefoil knot. For each $n &amp;gt; 0$, we can twists the designated strands to get a different tangle, and each of these tangles correspond to the quotient tangle of a torus knot. So far it seems that the nth tangle corresponds to the nth torus knot, though I still need to verify some more examples for higher $n$. I wonder how I would prove this? I would need to show the twists on the torus correspond to the n twists on the designated strands. The second family from surgery on the first family. I am not sure how exactly it is done, but we can take the designated strand and “wrap” it around the the top band. The case $m = 1$ is shown on the right. The third family comes surgery on the second family. For fixed $n, m$, we can let $k$ be some intger, and add $k$ twists inside the rectange (positive means positively sloped twists, negative is negatively sloped twists). I should be able to categorize all of the quotient tangles I have found so far with 5 crossings or less in these 3 families. From 5 crossings onward, I will hopefully find some more interesting families.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Week 10</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/Week10" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Week 10" /><published>2019-07-06T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-07-06T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/Week10</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/Week10">&lt;p&gt;Last week I used the KH program to calculate chain complexes for some simple tangles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week I am tasked with finding the minimal number of twists on the tangle such that the tail of the arc invariant chain complex dissapears.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Leon Yao</name></author><summary type="html">Last week I used the KH program to calculate chain complexes for some simple tangles. This week I am tasked with finding the minimal number of twists on the tangle such that the tail of the arc invariant chain complex dissapears.</summary></entry></feed>