<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://192.168.1.69:4000/ResearchJournal/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://192.168.1.69:4000/ResearchJournal/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-08-11T10:25:44-07:00</updated><id>http://192.168.1.69:4000/ResearchJournal/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Leon’s Summer Research Blog</title><subtitle>NSERC 2020</subtitle><author><name>Leon Yao</name></author><entry><title type="html">Week 13</title><link href="http://192.168.1.69:4000/ResearchJournal/Week12" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Week 13" /><published>2019-07-21T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-07-21T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://192.168.1.69:4000/ResearchJournal/Week12</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://192.168.1.69:4000/ResearchJournal/Week12">This week I am still trying to categorize capped trivial tangles into families.


&lt;!-- 

Last week I tried to calculate the 'small arc' invariant for some capped trivial tangles, but i misunderstand what makes the invariant small. I thought small meant that the last part of the chain dissapears, but I only need to count the number of vertices. 

So far I know that the immersed curve invariant corresponds some set of curves on the $4$ punctured disk.  
It turns out that adding positive or negative twists to the ends of the tangle corresponds to switching the punctures on the $4$ punctured disk, which in turns simplifies the tangle. I am tasked with calculating the small arc for different rational tangles, and experimenting to see how different twists affect the invariant. (The invariant is unique up to these kinds of twists). 

I am also tasked with categorizing the capped trivial tangles into families. So far I know of 3 families. 

The first family comes from the quotient of the trefoil knot. 
&lt;img src = &quot;{{site.baseurl}}/assets/img/7-15-2020-1.jpg&quot;&gt; 
For each $n &gt; 0$, we can twists the designated strands to get a different tangle, and each of these tangles correspond to the quotient tangle of a torus knot. So far it seems that the nth tangle corresponds to the nth torus knot, though I still need to verify some more examples for higher $n$. I wonder how I would prove this? I would need to show the twists on the torus correspond to the n twists on the designated strands. 

The second family from surgery on the first family. I am not sure how exactly it is done, but we can take the designated strand and &quot;wrap&quot; it around the the top band. The case $m = 1$ is shown on the right.
&lt;img src = &quot;{{site.baseurl}}/assets/img/7-15-2020-2.jpg&quot;&gt; 

The third family comes surgery on the second family. For fixed $n, m$, we can let $k$ be some intger, and add $k$ twists inside the rectange (positive means positively sloped twists, negative is negatively sloped twists). 
&lt;img src = &quot;{{site.baseurl}}/assets/img/7-15-2020-3.jpg&quot;&gt; 

I should be able to categorize all of the quotient tangles I have found so far with 5 crossings or less in these 3 families. From 5 crossings onward, I will hopefully find some more interesting families.   --&gt;</content><author><name>Leon Yao</name></author><summary type="html">This week I am still trying to categorize capped trivial tangles into families.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Immersed Curve Invariant</title><link href="http://192.168.1.69:4000/ResearchJournal/ImmersedCurveInvariant" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Immersed Curve Invariant" /><published>2019-07-17T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-07-17T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://192.168.1.69:4000/ResearchJournal/ImmersedCurveInvariant</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://192.168.1.69:4000/ResearchJournal/ImmersedCurveInvariant">I talked with Ben Garbuz today and he taught me a bit about the Immersed Curve Invariant and how it's related to Khovanov homology. 

Given a 4 ended tangle, we will designate each of the 4 ends to become part of a boundary of a 3 punctured disk. 

For example, given the rational tangle with 1 negative twist, we would transform the tangle into the following diagram

&lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/ImmersedCurveInvariant/ImmersedCurveInvariant-1.jpg&quot;&gt;

We then stretch the strand of tangle that does not have a star end point, such that so the end points of the red curve on the punctures correspond to the endpoints of the tangle. 

We will label the diagram will the following symbols, so that we can represent the homotopy class of the curve in a simpler way. 

&lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/ImmersedCurveInvariant/ImmersedCurveInvariant-2.jpg&quot;&gt;

From here, we can construct the chain complex over the ring generated by the $S, D$ cobordisms. 

I have been told that we assume the curve always has a counterclockwise orientation, but it doesn't match up with the program...

We do this by splitting the curve up into whenever it touches one of the dark green lines. The above curve would have 3 sections.
For every section that doesn't go into puncture, we will label it by S or D, depending on which of the S, D directions it follows on the boundary. From there, we construct the chain complex by with chain groups represented by the black or white dots, and boundary operators labelled with S and D. 

The above curve would have chain complex 

&lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/ImmersedCurveInvariant/ImmersedCurveInvariant-3.jpg&quot;&gt;

The curve can be used to calculate Khovanov Homology of the numerator closure of the tangle in the following way. For unreduced Khovanov homology, we draw the following orange curve. We then inspect the intersections between the red tangle curve and the orange curve. The number of intersections tells us how many copies of $\mathbb{F}$ there are in the homology. So here there would be 5 copies (This seems wrong, I think Ben told me you need to draw it in the minimal form, but I am not sure how to do that)

&lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/ImmersedCurveInvariant/ImmersedCurveInvariant-4.jpg&quot;&gt;


From there, there is a process upon where you first assign gradings to the intersections between the orange curve and the dark straight lines, and then from there you can follow the orange curve to find the gradings of the groups.</content><author><name>Leon Yao</name></author><summary type="html">I talked with Ben Garbuz today and he taught me a bit about the Immersed Curve Invariant and how it’s related to Khovanov homology. Given a 4 ended tangle, we will designate each of the 4 ends to become part of a boundary of a 3 punctured disk. For example, given the rational tangle with 1 negative twist, we would transform the tangle into the following diagram We then stretch the strand of tangle that does not have a star end point, such that so the end points of the red curve on the punctures correspond to the endpoints of the tangle. We will label the diagram will the following symbols, so that we can represent the homotopy class of the curve in a simpler way. From here, we can construct the chain complex over the ring generated by the $S, D$ cobordisms. I have been told that we assume the curve always has a counterclockwise orientation, but it doesn’t match up with the program… We do this by splitting the curve up into whenever it touches one of the dark green lines. The above curve would have 3 sections. For every section that doesn’t go into puncture, we will label it by S or D, depending on which of the S, D directions it follows on the boundary. From there, we construct the chain complex by with chain groups represented by the black or white dots, and boundary operators labelled with S and D. The above curve would have chain complex The curve can be used to calculate Khovanov Homology of the numerator closure of the tangle in the following way. For unreduced Khovanov homology, we draw the following orange curve. We then inspect the intersections between the red tangle curve and the orange curve. The number of intersections tells us how many copies of $\mathbb{F}$ there are in the homology. So here there would be 5 copies (This seems wrong, I think Ben told me you need to draw it in the minimal form, but I am not sure how to do that) From there, there is a process upon where you first assign gradings to the intersections between the orange curve and the dark straight lines, and then from there you can follow the orange curve to find the gradings of the groups.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Week 11</title><link href="http://192.168.1.69:4000/ResearchJournal/Week11" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Week 11" /><published>2019-07-13T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-07-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://192.168.1.69:4000/ResearchJournal/Week11</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://192.168.1.69:4000/ResearchJournal/Week11">Last week I tried to calculate the 'small arc' invariant for some capped trivial tangles, but i misunderstand what makes the invariant small. I thought small meant that the last part of the chain dissapears, but I only need to count the number of vertices. 

So far I know that the immersed curve invariant corresponds some set of curves on the $4$ punctured disk.  
It turns out that adding positive or negative twists to the ends of the tangle corresponds to switching the punctures on the $4$ punctured disk, which in turns simplifies the tangle. I am tasked with calculating the small arc for different rational tangles, and experimenting to see how different twists affect the invariant. (The invariant is unique up to these kinds of twists). 

I am also tasked with categorizing the capped trivial tangles into families. So far I know of 3 families. 

The first family comes from the quotient of the trefoil knot. 
&lt;img src = &quot;{{site.baseurl}}/assets/img/7-15-2020-1.jpg&quot;&gt; 
For each $n &gt; 0$, we can twists the designated strands to get a different tangle, and each of these tangles correspond to the quotient tangle of a torus knot. So far it seems that the nth tangle corresponds to the nth torus knot, though I still need to verify some more examples for higher $n$. I wonder how I would prove this? I would need to show the twists on the torus correspond to the n twists on the designated strands. 

The second family from surgery on the first family. I am not sure how exactly it is done, but we can take the designated strand and &quot;wrap&quot; it around the the top band. The case $m = 1$ is shown on the right.
&lt;img src = &quot;{{site.baseurl}}/assets/img/7-15-2020-2.jpg&quot;&gt; 

The third family comes surgery on the second family. For fixed $n, m$, we can let $k$ be some intger, and add $k$ twists inside the rectange (positive means positively sloped twists, negative is negatively sloped twists). 
&lt;img src = &quot;{{site.baseurl}}/assets/img/7-15-2020-3.jpg&quot;&gt; 

I should be able to categorize all of the quotient tangles I have found so far with 5 crossings or less in these 3 families. From 5 crossings onward, I will hopefully find some more interesting families.</content><author><name>Leon Yao</name></author><summary type="html">Last week I tried to calculate the ‘small arc’ invariant for some capped trivial tangles, but i misunderstand what makes the invariant small. I thought small meant that the last part of the chain dissapears, but I only need to count the number of vertices. So far I know that the immersed curve invariant corresponds some set of curves on the $4$ punctured disk. It turns out that adding positive or negative twists to the ends of the tangle corresponds to switching the punctures on the $4$ punctured disk, which in turns simplifies the tangle. I am tasked with calculating the small arc for different rational tangles, and experimenting to see how different twists affect the invariant. (The invariant is unique up to these kinds of twists). I am also tasked with categorizing the capped trivial tangles into families. So far I know of 3 families. The first family comes from the quotient of the trefoil knot. For each $n &amp;gt; 0$, we can twists the designated strands to get a different tangle, and each of these tangles correspond to the quotient tangle of a torus knot. So far it seems that the nth tangle corresponds to the nth torus knot, though I still need to verify some more examples for higher $n$. I wonder how I would prove this? I would need to show the twists on the torus correspond to the n twists on the designated strands. The second family from surgery on the first family. I am not sure how exactly it is done, but we can take the designated strand and “wrap” it around the the top band. The case $m = 1$ is shown on the right. The third family comes surgery on the second family. For fixed $n, m$, we can let $k$ be some intger, and add $k$ twists inside the rectange (positive means positively sloped twists, negative is negatively sloped twists). I should be able to categorize all of the quotient tangles I have found so far with 5 crossings or less in these 3 families. From 5 crossings onward, I will hopefully find some more interesting families.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Week 10</title><link href="http://192.168.1.69:4000/ResearchJournal/Week10" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Week 10" /><published>2019-07-06T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-07-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://192.168.1.69:4000/ResearchJournal/Week10</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://192.168.1.69:4000/ResearchJournal/Week10">Last week I used the KH program to calculate chain complexes for some simple tangles.

This week I am tasked with finding the minimal number of twists on the tangle such that the tail of the arc invariant chain complex dissapears.</content><author><name>Leon Yao</name></author><summary type="html">Last week I used the KH program to calculate chain complexes for some simple tangles. This week I am tasked with finding the minimal number of twists on the tangle such that the tail of the arc invariant chain complex dissapears.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Week 9</title><link href="http://192.168.1.69:4000/ResearchJournal/Week9" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Week 9" /><published>2019-06-29T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-06-29T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://192.168.1.69:4000/ResearchJournal/Week9</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://192.168.1.69:4000/ResearchJournal/Week9">Last week I continued to polish tangles. I find it tricky to perform &quot;band&quot; R1 moves, as there are often strands that go through the band, and it is hard to visualize what happens to the band. 

This week I am tasked with using the python program to calculate Khovanov refinement for simple tangles. It is interesting to convert the drawings I've made to the format the program uses.</content><author><name>Leon Yao</name></author><summary type="html">Last week I continued to polish tangles. I find it tricky to perform “band” R1 moves, as there are often strands that go through the band, and it is hard to visualize what happens to the band. This week I am tasked with using the python program to calculate Khovanov refinement for simple tangles. It is interesting to convert the drawings I’ve made to the format the program uses.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Week 8</title><link href="http://192.168.1.69:4000/ResearchJournal/Week8" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Week 8" /><published>2019-06-22T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-06-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://192.168.1.69:4000/ResearchJournal/Week8</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://192.168.1.69:4000/ResearchJournal/Week8">This week I polished the simplified tangles. I am planning to create a site using the knot atlas template, to display invariants for each tangle.</content><author><name>Leon Yao</name></author><summary type="html">This week I polished the simplified tangles. I am planning to create a site using the knot atlas template, to display invariants for each tangle.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Week 7</title><link href="http://192.168.1.69:4000/ResearchJournal/Week7" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Week 7" /><published>2019-06-15T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-06-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://192.168.1.69:4000/ResearchJournal/Week7</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://192.168.1.69:4000/ResearchJournal/Week7">This week I redrew some capped trivial tangles. I tried to draw them as simplified as possible.</content><author><name>Leon Yao</name></author><summary type="html">This week I redrew some capped trivial tangles. I tried to draw them as simplified as possible.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Week 6</title><link href="http://192.168.1.69:4000/ResearchJournal/Week6" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Week 6" /><published>2019-06-08T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-06-08T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://192.168.1.69:4000/ResearchJournal/Week6</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://192.168.1.69:4000/ResearchJournal/Week6">I moved the Capped-Trivial-Tangles to a different site so I could add some buttons that show the construction of the tangle.</content><author><name>Leon Yao</name></author><summary type="html">I moved the Capped-Trivial-Tangles to a different site so I could add some buttons that show the construction of the tangle.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Week 5</title><link href="http://192.168.1.69:4000/ResearchJournal/Week5" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Week 5" /><published>2019-06-01T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-06-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://192.168.1.69:4000/ResearchJournal/Week5</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://192.168.1.69:4000/ResearchJournal/Week5">This week I drew some more Capped Trivial Tangles.
I also learned about a bit about the refined khovanov homology. 
I am excited to learn more about spectral sequences!</content><author><name>Leon Yao</name></author><summary type="html">This week I drew some more Capped Trivial Tangles. I also learned about a bit about the refined khovanov homology. I am excited to learn more about spectral sequences!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Chain Complexes</title><link href="http://192.168.1.69:4000/ResearchJournal/ChainComplexes" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Chain Complexes" /><published>2019-05-27T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-05-27T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://192.168.1.69:4000/ResearchJournal/ChainComplexes</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://192.168.1.69:4000/ResearchJournal/ChainComplexes">&lt;style&gt;
div.a {
  margin-left: 200px;
  width: 5px;
  height: 5px;
  top: -45px;
  transform: rotate(90deg);
  position: relative;
}
img {
    display: block;
    margin-left: auto;
    margin-right: auto;
    }
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;!-- If you look at the definition of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chain_complex#Definitions&quot;&gt;Chain Complex &lt;/a&gt; you will see a lot of scary words like &quot;differential&quot; and &quot;cochain&quot;. 

I want to try and motivate the usefulness of Chain Complexes without using any of those hard words.  --&gt;

Let's begin with some geometry. Take a piece of paper. Roll it up into a cylinder by gluing along an edge. Then fold the ends into a doughnut shape by gluing along a circle. 

Here is a hard question to answer. Is there a way to deform the doughnut back into the flat piece of paper with using scissors?

If you try it yourself you would probably guess not. One of the things you might say is a problem is that the donut has this hole in the middle.</content><author><name>Leon Yao</name></author><summary type="html">Let’s begin with some geometry. Take a piece of paper. Roll it up into a cylinder by gluing along an edge. Then fold the ends into a doughnut shape by gluing along a circle. Here is a hard question to answer. Is there a way to deform the doughnut back into the flat piece of paper with using scissors? If you try it yourself you would probably guess not. One of the things you might say is a problem is that the donut has this hole in the middle.</summary></entry></feed>